<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Df on Prabhat-The Temple of Art</title>
    <link>https://www.prabhatha.com/tags/df/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Df on Prabhat-The Temple of Art</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 14:38:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.prabhatha.com/tags/df/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Kruthika Tyagarajan</title>
      <link>https://www.prabhatha.com/training/faculty/dance-faculty/kruthika-tyagarajan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 14:38:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.prabhatha.com/training/faculty/dance-faculty/kruthika-tyagarajan/</guid>
      <description>Kruthika Tyagarajan: Kruthika Tyagarajan has been trained in classical Bharatanatyam dance form a very young age under the able tutelage of Guru. Smt. Shakuntala R Prabhat. She has successfully performed her Ranga Pravesha and has completed senior dance examination conducted by Karnataka Secondary Education Board.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chaithra Ananth</title>
      <link>https://www.prabhatha.com/training/faculty/dance-faculty/chaithra-ananth/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 14:37:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.prabhatha.com/training/faculty/dance-faculty/chaithra-ananth/</guid>
      <description>Chaithra Ananth: Chaithra Ananth is a senior dancer, who has been training in Bharatanatyam from the age of 6, under the able tutelage of Guru. Shakuntala R Prabhat. Apart from being a principal dancer at Prabhat Arts International and SAMUDYATA, Chaithra has given several solo performances at various prestigious platforms like World Dance Day at Sai Nrithyothsava, Shivaratri Festival, Bhadrachala Ramdhas Charitham, Tyagaraja Vybhavam, Nruthyadithya, Niranatara Narmada and many others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sheetal Umbrey</title>
      <link>https://www.prabhatha.com/training/faculty/dance-faculty/sheetal-umbrey/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 14:36:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.prabhatha.com/training/faculty/dance-faculty/sheetal-umbrey/</guid>
      <description>Sheetal Umbrey: Sheetal began her journey in Bharatanatyam at the age of 8 and ever since then, this vigilant youngster has been taking a keen interest in learning about the birth, history and future of Indian culture under the direction of Guru.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>