<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Abouts on Prabhat Arts International - The Temple of Art | Academy of Dance &amp; Theatre Art</title>
    <link>https://www.prabhatha.com/about/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Abouts on Prabhat Arts International - The Temple of Art | Academy of Dance &amp; Theatre Art</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 09:28:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.prabhatha.com/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Aacharya Raghavendra J Prabhat</title>
      <link>https://www.prabhatha.com/about/artistic-directors/aacharya-raghavendra-j-prabhat/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 09:28:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.prabhatha.com/about/artistic-directors/aacharya-raghavendra-j-prabhat/</guid>
      <description>Aacharya Raghavendra J Prabhat:  Aacharya Raghavendra J Prabhat hails from the culturally rich Lineage of Saint Poet Purandara Dasaru, Father of Carnatic Classical Music. Often termed as an intellectual orator, Aacharya Raghavendra J Prabhat, is a writer, literati, director, philosopher, poet, Costume designer and one of Karnataka’s foremost cultural figures, well versed in diverse fields of music, dance, theatre, and spiritualism.
An able cultural ambassador, Aacharya Raghavendra, has travelled the length and breadth of India and foreign countries like USA, Malaysia, Singapore, Switzerland, and the like, spreading the fragrance of the Indian culture and heritage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About | Academy of Dance and Theatre Art | Prabhat - The Temple of Art</title>
      <link>https://www.prabhatha.com/about/about_prabhat/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 09:28:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.prabhatha.com/about/about_prabhat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;about-us&#34;&gt;About us&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prabhat, The Temple of Art is an internationally renowned artistic institution from India. The organization has created stage history with a unique blend of tradition along with sophisticated stage techniques of the present technological era.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Overview</title>
      <link>https://www.prabhatha.com/about/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 09:28:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.prabhatha.com/about/overview/</guid>
      <description> Prabhat was established in 1930 and ever since then; the organization has been involved in serving and contributing to society through its offerings. Prabhat is known for,
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guru Shakuntala R Prabhath</title>
      <link>https://www.prabhatha.com/about/artistic-directors/guru-shakuntala-r-prabhath/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 08:28:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.prabhatha.com/about/artistic-directors/guru-shakuntala-r-prabhath/</guid>
      <description>Guru Shakuntala R Prabhath:  Shakuntala R Prabhath is one of Karnataka’s many splendid artists. A classical Bharatanatyam dancer and prime Natuvanar par excellence, Guru. Shakuntala is trained in Bharatanatyam style of dance under the renowned guru Smt. Narmada.
Guru. Smt. Shakuntala, apart from being a Bharatanatyam dancer, is also trained in martial arts, folk dances and yoga. A splendid artist and dance choreographer, Shakuntala, has choreographed several dance dramas, plays and dance productions for stage and television.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bharat R Prabhath</title>
      <link>https://www.prabhatha.com/about/artistic-directors/bharat-r-prabhath/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 07:28:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.prabhatha.com/about/artistic-directors/bharat-r-prabhath/</guid>
      <description>Bharat R Prabhath:  Bharat R Prabhath hails from the illustrious family of Prabhath. The originative highbrow was exposed to the values of Indian arts, culture and traditions from a very young age.
Bharat began his formal training in Kathak in the year 2004 under the able guidance of Smt Nirupama and Shri Rajendra. He has had the opportunity to tour across the country and abroad and participate in a number of programmes at prestigious festivals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sharat R Prabhath</title>
      <link>https://www.prabhatha.com/about/artistic-directors/sharat-r-prabhath/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 06:28:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.prabhatha.com/about/artistic-directors/sharat-r-prabhath/</guid>
      <description>Sharat R Prabhath:  Sharat has had the fortune of being very closely associated with Indian arts and culture from a very young age. He began his training in Carnatic classical music under the able guidance of Dr Hamsini Nagendra. He now continues to learn under Karnataka Kalashree – Tirumale Srinivas.
Sharat is also undergoing training in the classical dance style of Kathak for many years under the able tutelage of the famous dancing duo, Smt.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>