<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tdp on Prabhat - The Temple of Art | Academy of Dance and Theatre Art | Blend of Tradition and Elegance</title>
    <link>https://www.prabhatha.com/tags/tdp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tdp on Prabhat - The Temple of Art | Academy of Dance and Theatre Art | Blend of Tradition and Elegance</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 20:08:11 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.prabhatha.com/tags/tdp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>7 Rays of 7 Hills</title>
      <link>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/thematic-dance-productions/7-rays-of-7-hills/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 20:08:11 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/thematic-dance-productions/7-rays-of-7-hills/</guid>
      <description>7 Rays of 7 Hills: The entire universe is filled with colours and every colour has an interpretation. 7 Rays of 7 Hills interprets the colourful rays as the rays of grace by the Lord of 7 hills, Srinivasa. 7 Rays of 7 Hills is an enchanting classical dance, which depicts that one can draw the 7 colourful rays (personifying the 7 chakras) of devotion towards the self just by soaking in the ecstasy of devotion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fantasy of Flute</title>
      <link>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/thematic-dance-productions/fantasy-of-flute/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 20:08:11 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/thematic-dance-productions/fantasy-of-flute/</guid>
      <description>Fantasy of Flute An imaginative and fantastical dance musical - Fantasy of Flute personifies the beauty of love through music. Every being in love with the ultimate seeks to possess his/her love completely. In the advent of possession, one will have to lose love. The same phenomenon is seen in “_Bhagavatha_” - where Bhagavan Vyasa beautifully explains the theory of absence and presence through the story of Lord Krushna. The fantasy of Flute is a contemporary presentation of the traditional story from Bhagavatha Purana depicting theory of absence and presence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guru Vandana</title>
      <link>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/thematic-dance-productions/guru-vandana/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 20:08:11 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/thematic-dance-productions/guru-vandana/</guid>
      <description>Guru Vandana A very innovative concept that talks about the greatness of a guru using the text from the Vedas, Upanishads and stories from the Puranas.
Concept: Sharat R Prabhat
Choreography: Guru. Smt Shakuntala R Prabhat
Music: RoSha (Rohit Bhat and Sharat R Prabhat)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Purushasuktha</title>
      <link>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/thematic-dance-productions/purushasuktha/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 20:08:11 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/thematic-dance-productions/purushasuktha/</guid>
      <description>Purushasuktha: The Mahabharata says, whose prowess not even all the gods can ever imagine. Such is the sage to whom Purushasuktha was revealed and who then gave expression to it as the hymn on the Supreme Purusha. Purushasuktha is a unique depiction of the Supreme Personality, using 4 different techniques or paths to realise the ultimate. The paths being: Vedic Rituals, Yoga, Music, and Dance. Purushasuktha is a pioneering experiment which blends all the four paths in a single production.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shilpa Kala Vybhava - The Sculpturous Marvel</title>
      <link>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/thematic-dance-productions/shilpa-kala-vybhava-the-sculpturous-marvel-/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 20:08:11 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/thematic-dance-productions/shilpa-kala-vybhava-the-sculpturous-marvel-/</guid>
      <description>Shilpa Kala Vybhava - The Sculpturous Marvel India is known for the culture and heritage she totes in her. The sculpturous marvel is a unique dance production which brings into light the greatest architectural marvel and the sculptural heritage of our country. Inspired by the Hoysala Dancing Queen, Shantala and the dynastic history of Hoysalas, who ruled in the 12th Century, Shilpa Kala Vybhava creates fantasies on stage by bringing the sculptures into life by the artistic touch of Shantala Devi.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>