<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PrabhatRepertoire on Prabhat - The Temple of Art | Academy of Dance and Theatre Art | Blend of Tradition and Elegance</title>
    <link>https://www.prabhatha.com/tags/prabhatrepertoire/</link>
    <description>Recent content in PrabhatRepertoire on Prabhat - The Temple of Art | Academy of Dance and Theatre Art | Blend of Tradition and Elegance</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 20:08:11 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.prabhatha.com/tags/prabhatrepertoire/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>7 Rays of 7 Hills</title>
      <link>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/thematic-dance-productions/7-rays-of-7-hills/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 20:08:11 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/thematic-dance-productions/7-rays-of-7-hills/</guid>
      <description>7 Rays of 7 Hills: The entire universe is filled with colours and every colour has an interpretation. 7 Rays of 7 Hills interprets the colourful rays as the rays of grace by the Lord of 7 hills, Srinivasa. 7 Rays of 7 Hills is an enchanting classical dance, which depicts that one can draw the 7 colourful rays (personifying the 7 chakras) of devotion towards the self just by soaking in the ecstasy of devotion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classical dance sequences</title>
      <link>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/classical-dance-sequences/indu-nee-karedu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 20:08:11 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/classical-dance-sequences/indu-nee-karedu/</guid>
      <description>The company has a mountainous list of classical compositions that include compositions of Haridasas, Vachana Kartas, Keertanakars like Tygaraja and Dikshitar, Works of contemporary poets and the like.
 Indu Nee Karedu: The classical style of Bharatanatyam involves various genres of composition which add to the form’s completeness. Indu Nee Karedu is a Jaavali where the dancer displays her love for the partner in his absence.
Concept: Raghavendra J Prabhat</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fantasy of Flute</title>
      <link>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/thematic-dance-productions/fantasy-of-flute/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 20:08:11 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/thematic-dance-productions/fantasy-of-flute/</guid>
      <description>Fantasy of Flute An imaginative and fantastical dance musical - Fantasy of Flute personifies the beauty of love through music. Every being in love with the ultimate seeks to possess his/her love completely. In the advent of possession, one will have to lose love. The same phenomenon is seen in “Bhagavatha” - where Bhagavan Vyasa beautifully explains the theory of absence and presence through the story of Lord Krushna. The fantasy of Flute is a contemporary presentation of the traditional story from Bhagavatha Purana depicting theory of absence and presence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Guru Vandana</title>
      <link>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/thematic-dance-productions/guru-vandana/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 20:08:11 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/thematic-dance-productions/guru-vandana/</guid>
      <description>Guru Vandana A very innovative concept that talks about the greatness of a guru using the text from the Vedas, Upanishads and stories from the Puranas.
Concept: Sharat R Prabhat
Choreography: Guru. Smt Shakuntala R Prabhat
Music: RoSha (Rohit Bhat and Sharat R Prabhat)
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kapi Tillana</title>
      <link>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/classical-dance-sequences/kapi-tillana/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 20:08:11 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/classical-dance-sequences/kapi-tillana/</guid>
      <description>Kapi Tillana: A Tillana is a rhythm driven composition that is performed at the end of a recital. Kapi Tillana describes the beauty of Lord Nataraja and ecstasy one experiences in watching the Lord of Dance perform ‘Aananda Tandava.’
Concept:
Choreography: Shakuntala R Prabhat
Music:
Duration: 8 mins
Dancers: Solo and Group
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kathaastra</title>
      <link>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/dance-drama-ballets/kathaastra/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 20:08:11 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/dance-drama-ballets/kathaastra/</guid>
      <description>Kathaastra: Kathastra, as the name suggests, is a unique blend of Harikatha, Kavya, World Music, 3D Visuals, and five forms of World Dance. A novel experiment that contemporised the eternal epic “Mahabharata” using unprecedented stage techniques. Kathaastra is an unrivalled Story Dance Musical which has been adapted from one of the most celebrated and worshipped Kannada Literatures, Karnata Bharatha Katha Manjari, created by Roopaka Samrajya Chakravarti, Kumara Vyasa.
Glimpse: Trailer</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Krishnashtotra Varna</title>
      <link>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/classical-dance-sequences/krishnashtotra-varna/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 20:08:11 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/classical-dance-sequences/krishnashtotra-varna/</guid>
      <description>Krishnashtotra Varna: As the name suggests, Sri Krishnah Kamalanatho is the only Sanskrit varna adapted to classical dance form of Bharatanatyam. The Varna has been adapted from Sri Krishnashtora Shathanama Stotra. The Varna depicts the entire life history of Lord Krushna as per the Stotra.
Concept and Compilation: Raghavendra J Prabhat
Choreography: Guru Narmada
Group Choreography: Shakuntala R Prabhat
Music: Tirumale Srinivas
Duration: 45 mins
Dancers: Group and Solo</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mohini Bhasmasura</title>
      <link>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/dance-drama-ballets/mohini-bhasmasura/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 20:08:11 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/dance-drama-ballets/mohini-bhasmasura/</guid>
      <description>Mohini Bhasmasura: The rivalry between the Gods and Demons had been going on for a long time. The demons had tried to conquer the Gods but all their efforts were foiled by the Superior Gods. Mohini Bhasmasura is one such Dance Drama which gives to an audience an experience of vibrancy, devotion, grace, humour, terror and finally, peace. A very well appreciated dance drama, Mohini Bhasmasura is a Mythological story with a contemporary touch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Namah Parvati Pathe</title>
      <link>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/classical-dance-sequences/namah-parvati-pathe/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 20:08:11 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/classical-dance-sequences/namah-parvati-pathe/</guid>
      <description>Namah Parvati Pathe: A devotional recital on God of Gods, Veerupaksha / Shiva. This sequence describes the ornaments, compassion and the life story of Lord Shiva using vibrant dance moves of Bharatanatyam
Concept: Raghavendra J Prabhat
Choreography: Shakuntala R Prabhat
Music: Tirumale Srinivas
Duration: 8 mins
Dancers: Group and Solo
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Namo Tulasi</title>
      <link>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/classical-dance-sequences/namo-tulasi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 20:08:11 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/classical-dance-sequences/namo-tulasi/</guid>
      <description>Namo Tulasi: A special classical sequence on the sacred plant - Tulsi. Indian civilization has always regarded nature as a divine source of energy and amongst all the plants, Tulsi takes the prime position. Namo Tulasi is an experimental presentation where the dancer/s describe the attributes, grace of Goddess Tulasi.
Concept: Raghavendra J Prabhat
Choreography: Shakuntala R Prabhat
Music: Tirumale Srinivas
Duration: 10 mins
Dancers: Group and Solo
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Narasimha Stuti</title>
      <link>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/classical-dance-sequences/narasimha-stuti/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 20:08:11 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/classical-dance-sequences/narasimha-stuti/</guid>
      <description>Narasimha Stuti: Bharatanatyam cult consists in its tradition devotional recitals, and Narasimha Stuti is one such composition of the father of Carnatic music, Purandara Dasaru. Here, saint poet speaks about the greatness of compassion the almighty displayed upon his ace enemy Hiranya Kashyapu.
Concept: Raghavendra J Prabhat
Choreography: Shakuntala R Prabhat
Music: Pandit Vijay Raghava Rao
Duration: 10 mins
Dancers: Group and Solo
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Navarasa Varna</title>
      <link>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/classical-dance-sequences/navarasa-varna/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 20:08:11 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/classical-dance-sequences/navarasa-varna/</guid>
      <description>Navarasa Varna: A varna in the classical dance form of Bharatanatyam is usually single rasa/essence/quality oriented. Navarasa Varna is a unique experiment that portrays 9 qualities/rasas of Lord Sri Krushna with specific episodes in Kannada. Navarasa Krushna Varna is an unprecedented classical experiment over the years.
Concept and Lyrics: Raghavendra J Prabhat
Choreography: Shakuntala R Prabhat
Music: Tirumale Srinivas
Duration: 40 mins
Dancers: Group and Solo
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pibata Bhagavatam Rasamalayam</title>
      <link>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/dance-drama-ballets/pibata-bhagavatam-rasamalayam/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 20:08:11 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/dance-drama-ballets/pibata-bhagavatam-rasamalayam/</guid>
      <description>Pibata Bhagavatam Rasamalayam Among all the Puranas, Bhagavata Purana is considered as “Maha Purana.” Pibata Bhagavatam Rasamalayam is a complete production in the style of a Dance Drama. This Ballet, in a splendid fashion, narrates the entire essence of Bhagavata Mahapurana in 90 minutes. Our audiences opine that Pibata Bhagavatam Rasamalayam is one such ballet which is crafted for people of all backgrounds and cultures.
Concept: Raghavendra J Prabhat
Choreography: Udupi Lakshmi Narayanaacharya and Shakuntala R Prabhat</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prahladam Vande Jagath Gurum</title>
      <link>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/dance-drama-ballets/prahladam-vande-jagath-gurum/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 20:08:11 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/dance-drama-ballets/prahladam-vande-jagath-gurum/</guid>
      <description>Prahladam Vande Jagath Gurum: A special dance production for a niche audience who believe in the philosophy of devotion - Bhakti Pantha. Prahlada, though a son of the greatest demon in the epics of India - Hiranyakashyapu propagated the idea of strength in devotion. Prahladam Vande Jagath Gurum, is a complete snapshot of the life history of Prahlada. A traditional dance drama style of presentation, Prahladam Vande Jagathgurum has been adapted from Sage Vyasa’s ‘Bhagavatha’ maha purana.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Punyakoti</title>
      <link>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/dance-drama-ballets/punyakoti/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 20:08:11 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/dance-drama-ballets/punyakoti/</guid>
      <description>Punyakoti: Famous folklore of Karnataka, Punyakoti - which is even to the present day sung in every household of Karnataka, portrays the triumph of non-violence over violence and cruelty. A poem that narrates the story of how a cow being caught by a ferocious tiger transforms the very nature of the canine by treading the path of truth. A fictitious story, Punyakoti propagates the idea, “Satyameva Jayate” - “The Truth Alone Triumphs”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Purushasuktha</title>
      <link>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/thematic-dance-productions/purushasuktha/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 20:08:11 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/thematic-dance-productions/purushasuktha/</guid>
      <description>Purushasuktha: The Mahabharata says, whose prowess not even all the gods can ever imagine. Such is the sage to whom Purushasuktha was revealed and who then gave expression to it as the hymn on the Supreme Purusha. Purushasuktha is a unique depiction of the Supreme Personality, using 4 different techniques or paths to realise the ultimate. The paths being: Vedic Rituals, Yoga, Music, and Dance. Purushasuktha is a pioneering experiment which blends all the four paths in a single production.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pushpanjali Malahari, Mand and Amrutavarshini</title>
      <link>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/classical-dance-sequences/pushpanjali-malahari-mand-and-amrutavarshini/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 20:08:11 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/classical-dance-sequences/pushpanjali-malahari-mand-and-amrutavarshini/</guid>
      <description>Pushpanjali Malahari, Mand and Amrutavarshini: Pushpanjali is the invocation dance in the classical tradition of Bharatanatyam. Here, the dancer/s offer their salutations to the rangasthala / stage and the Lord of Dance Nataraja with pushpa - Flowers and Anjali - Folded Hands in reverence. In the above-mentioned Pushpanjalies the dancer/s offer their salutations to Lord Ganesha, Lord Nataraja, Goddess Saraswathi and Goddess Parvathi to wash away all the obstacles and sins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saptaswara Saraswati</title>
      <link>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/classical-dance-sequences/saptaswara-saraswati/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 20:08:11 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/classical-dance-sequences/saptaswara-saraswati/</guid>
      <description>Saptaswara Saraswati: A special sequence where Goddess Saraswati is worshipped through the delicacies of music. The Carnatic music comprises 7 swaras - which is the actual translation of ‘Sapta Swara.’ And every Swara has a significance.
 षड्जं मयूरो वदति | गावस्तु ऋषभ भाशिनह | अजाविकस्तु गान्धारम् | क्रौन्चः कुवणति मध्यमं | पुश्पसाधारणे काळे पिकःकूजति पञ्चमं | धैवतं हेसते वाजि | निशादम् ब्रह्मते गजह | मयूरादयह मत्ता गायन्ति स्वर सप्तकं ||</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shilpa Kala Vybhava - The Sculpturous Marvel</title>
      <link>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/thematic-dance-productions/shilpa-kala-vybhava-the-sculpturous-marvel-/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 20:08:11 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/thematic-dance-productions/shilpa-kala-vybhava-the-sculpturous-marvel-/</guid>
      <description>Shilpa Kala Vybhava - The Sculpturous Marvel India is known for the culture and heritage she totes in her. The sculpturous marvel is a unique dance production which brings into light the greatest architectural marvel and the sculptural heritage of our country. Inspired by the Hoysala Dancing Queen, Shantala and the dynastic history of Hoysalas, who ruled in the 12th Century, Shilpa Kala Vybhava creates fantasies on stage by bringing the sculptures into life by the artistic touch of Shantala Devi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shrinivasa Kalyana</title>
      <link>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/dance-drama-ballets/shrinivasa-kalyana/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 20:08:11 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/dance-drama-ballets/shrinivasa-kalyana/</guid>
      <description>Shrinivasa Kalyana: This novel presentation “Sreenivasa Kalyana” integrates the conceptual and the symbolic aspects of the “intellect” and the mind. The first half unfolds with the universal concept of the macro unifying with the micro. The audience can envisage the process of ultimate realization through the unparalleled story of Lord Srinivasa.
Concept: Raghavendra J Prabhat
Choreography: Shakuntala R Prabhat and Sathya Narayan Raju
Music: Praveen D Rao
Duration: 90 mins</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shrungara Varna</title>
      <link>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/classical-dance-sequences/shrungara-varna/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 20:08:11 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/classical-dance-sequences/shrungara-varna/</guid>
      <description>Shrungara Varna: A unique Bharatanatyam Varna in Kannada which is based on the Shrungara Rasa/quality - the quality of romance or love. Shrungara Varna is an unprecedented experiment, where the Lord of Love, Manmatha (Cupid) is glorified. Every trait of Manmatha and the life history of Manmatha is captured in the Varna.
Concept and Lyrics: Raghavendra J Prabhat
Choreography: Shakuntala R Prabhat
Music: Tirumale Srinivas
Duration: 45 mins
Dancers: Group and Solo</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sundarangi</title>
      <link>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/classical-dance-sequences/sundarangi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 20:08:11 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/classical-dance-sequences/sundarangi/</guid>
      <description>Sundarangi: A Jaavali which depicts the predicament of the Nayika pining for her beloved. Sundarangi beautifully expresses the intricacies of feminism. Sundarangi is a contemporary concept with a blend of the traditional dance form.
Concept: Raghavendra J Prabhat
Choreography: Shakuntala R Prabhat
Music: Tirumale Srinivas
Duration: 8 mins
Dancers: Solo
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tamasoma Jyotirgamaya</title>
      <link>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/dance-drama-ballets/tamasoma-jyotirgamaya/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 20:08:11 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.prabhatha.com/repertoire/dance-drama-ballets/tamasoma-jyotirgamaya/</guid>
      <description>Tamasoma Jyotirgamaya: Tamasoma Jyotirgamaya is a newfangled ballet which literally means - ‘From Darkness unto Light.’ Tamasoma Jyotirgamaya is a pioneering attempt made by Prabhat in 2003 for the Anti-Terrorism conclave held at Delhi. Say no to terrorism or Tamasoma Jyotirgamaya is an experimental presentation which presents the victory of positivity and peace over negativity and terrorism in a contemporary way with 3d audiovisuals and true stories.
Concept: Raghavendra J Prabhat</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>