<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fac on Prabhat Arts International - The Temple of Art | Academy of Dance &amp; Theatre Art</title>
    <link>https://www.prabhatha.com/tags/fac/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fac on Prabhat Arts International - The Temple of Art | Academy of Dance &amp; Theatre Art</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 14:40:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.prabhatha.com/tags/fac/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dance Faculty</title>
      <link>https://www.prabhatha.com/training/faculty/dance-faculty/chaithra-ananth/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 14:40:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.prabhatha.com/training/faculty/dance-faculty/chaithra-ananth/</guid>
      <description>Chaithra Ananth Chaithra Ananth is a senior dancer, who has been training in Bharatanatyam from the age of 6, under the able tutelage of Guru. Shakuntala R Prabhat. Apart from being a principal dancer at Prabhat Arts International and SAMUDYATA, Chaithra has given several solo performances at various prestigious platforms like World Dance Day at Sai Nrithyothsava, Shivaratri Festival, Bhadrachala Ramdhas Charitham, Tyagaraja Vybhavam, Nruthyadithya, Niranatara Narmada and many others. She holds a masters degree in Dance - Bharatanatyam and Bharata Nruthyam.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.prabhatha.com/training/faculty/dance-faculty/kruthika-tyagarajan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 14:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.prabhatha.com/training/faculty/dance-faculty/kruthika-tyagarajan/</guid>
      <description>Kruthika Tyagarajan Kruthika Tyagarajan has been trained in classical Bharatanatyam dance form a very young age under the able tutelage of Guru. Smt. Shakuntala R Prabhat. She has successfully performed her Ranga Pravesha and has completed senior dance examination conducted by Karnataka Secondary Education Board. A Grade B artist of Doordarshan, Kruthika has travelled the length and breadth of the country performing for esteemed institutions and forums like Ankura, IIT - Mumbai, Vishwa Kannada Sammelana and many others.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://www.prabhatha.com/training/faculty/dance-faculty/sheetal-umbrey/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 14:39:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.prabhatha.com/training/faculty/dance-faculty/sheetal-umbrey/</guid>
      <description>Sheetal Umbrey Sheetal began her journey in Bharatanatyam at the age of 8 and ever since then, this vigilant youngster has been taking a keen interest in learning about the birth, history and future of Indian culture under the direction of Guru. Smt Shakuntala R Prabhat. Sheetal has taken active participation in all dance productions of Prabhat Arts International. Apart from group productions, the dancer has also given solo performances at various prestigious platforms across the country.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Music Faculty</title>
      <link>https://www.prabhatha.com/training/faculty/music-faculty/rohit-bhat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 14:38:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.prabhatha.com/training/faculty/music-faculty/rohit-bhat/</guid>
      <description>Rohit Bhat Rohit Bhat has completed Vidwath exams in Carnatic Classical music under the able tutoring of Vid. S Shankar. An Ananya awardee, Rohit Bhat, is an active artist at Radio Mirchi 98.Rohit Bhat has extensively performed for various festivals at National and International level. A play-back vocalist, Rohit, has also performed for AIR. Rohit Bhat takes a keen interest in composing music for various institutions and forums like Prabhata, Bimba, Jain Group of Institutions, BMS College of Engineering, VTU Festivals, Bharat Vikas Parishad and several others.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
